Arpit Agarwal

E-mail: arpitec2706@gmail.com Mobile:+91 8527723094

Summary:

Overall six years of experience working as a cloud Engineer with passion for cloud technologies. I have been developing my expertise in AZURE/GCP and Devops. While constructing my career, by learning required technologies such as Linux and Devops tools to better experiment with cloud, I am all geared up for the challenging work environment, where I can contribute, and utilise my skills and abilities while learning new things to achive personal and organisational goals.

Technical Skills:

- Hands on in GCP Skills(Compute Engine, Load Balancer, VPC, Storage, Cloud Functions, Stackdriver, Firewalls, Cloud SQL, Bigquery etc).
- Hands on in Azure Skills(VM,Storage,Resouce Group,Deployment Models,Network Security group,Virtual Network,Azure CLI,Load Balancer etc.)
- Good Experience in creating and configuring new Build jobs,Plug-ins Management, builds using Master/Slaves and administering task in Jenkins.
- Having hands-on experience in building the infrastructure using Terraform(infra as a code).
- Having hands-on in Containserisation tools like Docker, Kubernetes. Deploying images in Docker hub and various repository.
- Deploy Containers to cluster, meaning of VM's using Kubernetes.
- Deployment of new hosts in Google, Azure cloud.
- Managed system administration work on VM Instances.
- Setup web servers behind ELB with SSL on different cloud providers.
- Resolved problems in cloud applications by proper identification as per project requirements.
- Provided end to end support for serverless architecture.
- Proactive monitoring of cloud infrastructure using monitoring tools like Nutanix Beam, Nutanix Flow security control, Stackdriver etc.
- Knowledge of the TCP/IP networking and DNS,LDAP etc.
- Managing web servers (Apache, Glassfish, Rabbit MQ, Zookeper).
- Strong MySQL Database Administration experience (Hot & Cold Backups, Recovery, Replication etc)
- Hands-on experience in MySQL Database and PostgreSQL.
- Strong *nix Working & Administration Skills (Linux, Ubuntu,).
- Decent experience with Spinnaker using it as a deployment method.
- Log management tools.
- Worked as an integral part of the development team with troubleshooting, development and maintenance of systems.
- Basic understanding in the scripting language i.e. Python, Bash Scripting.

Professional Experience:

Working with WPP IT from Sept 20 to present

Senior Cloud Engineer as a part of Cloud Centre of Excellence team.

- Plan/Design the migration of on premises workloads to cloud in various platforms i.e. GCP/Azure.
- Building the infrastructure using terraform in GCP and automate the deployment using Cloud Build.
- Designing the landing zone in Azure portal for various clients for creation of the resources and services.
- Moving the resources, data, workloads in to cloud using cloud migration strategy.
- Learning to use logic apps in Azure for integration of the apps and building the connectors for the organization.
- Containerization of the application of clients using Docker, kubernentes.
- Review and manage technical requirements and business functional requirements to establish new could platforms and migration patterns.
- Create Continuous Integration and Deployment Pipelines.
- Support the Solution Architects with Low Level Designs.

Worked with Riversand Technologies, Bengaluru from Jan20 to August20.

Senior Cloud Operations Engineer

- Running SaaS applications smoothly and reliably for the customers.
- Performing the application upgrade for various customers as per the various releases.
- Respond to infrastructure monitoring alerts, resolving incidents to ensure system uptime and expected service levels.
- Building the infra in Azure cloud as per the customers application requirements using the ARM templates via Jenkins job.
- Monitoring the application/infra using Sensu, Grafana, Kibana logs.
- Building the ELK model for the application which helps in analyzing the logs at one central place in real time.
- Automation for monitoring part for receiving the alert in real time using Bash scripting.
- Setting up the authentication for the application using Okta/RSA/Auth0.
- Deploying the microservices in the container (Docker) using Jenkins.
- Setting up the Storage account/event hub for customer's data.
- Use infrastructure monitoring tools and respond to alerts to continuously improve stability of system.

Worked with GE Digital, Bengaluru from April 2019 to Jan 20.

Enterprise Application Engineer

Key roles and responsibilities-

- Working closely with cross functional team to deliver features and products.
- Drive usage of tools with global user through proactive support.
- Ensure on time completion of project deliverables and adhere to defined project management.
- Worked on BI tools Sisense to help clients to visualize there data in different formats.
- Migrated the BI tool application from windows server to linux server

Worked with Indecomm Global Services, Bengaluru from NOV 2017 to March 2019

Client- Actian(Hybrid Data Management Company)

Key roles and Responsibilities:

Software Engineer:

- Involved in build and maintain Highly Available secure multi-zone AWS cloud infrastructure utilizing AWS cloud formation.
- Experience in code deployment with tools such as Cloud Formation/Terraform
- Resource Config changes for increasing the VM template/settings. Binding services to the deployed applications.
- Setup of Cloud Watch alarms, setting up Cloud Trail, creating Cloud formation templates, creating S3 buckets.
- Configured aggregation of Cloud Trail logs across AWS accounts and reigon into single S3 bucket to perform security analysis, track changes to AWS resources, troubleshoot operational issues.
- Responsible for deploying SSL CERTS across AWS ELB and CLOUD FRONT.
- Involved in Buisness data for Disaster Recovery(DR) and upgrading to new instance types for better performance.

 Applied routing policies for AWS Route53 such as Latency Routing policy, Weighted Routing policy, Failover Routing policies based on Health check of resources.

Worked with HCL TECHNOLOGIES., NOIDA from SEPT 2015 to Nov 2017

Client- Novartis

Key Roles & Responsibilities:

AWS Admin(Analyst)

 Setup/Managing Linux Servers on Amazon (EC2, EBS, ELB, SSL, Security Groups, RDS and IAM).

- Setup/Managing VPC, Subnets; make connection between different zones; Blocking suspicious ip/subnet via ACL.
- Setup/Managing CDN on Amazon CloudFront (Origin Path: Server / S3) to improve site performance.
- Create/Managing buckets on S3 (CLI) and store db and logs backup, upload images for CDNserve.

Setup/Managing Databases on Amazon RDS. Monitoring servers thorough Amazon CloudWatch, SNS.

- Creating/Managing DNS records on Amazon Route 53.
- Creating/Managing AMI/Snapshots/Volumes, Upgrade/downgrade AWS resources (CPU, Memory, EBS)
- Creating AWS Instances and resources Bills.
- Involved in end to end activities for the company
- Focussed on improvements to build and deploymenttools.
- Architected and managed IT infrastructure on AWS various clients.
- Resolved problems in cloud applications by proper identification.

Backup Admin:

• Installing and configuring of Master/Media and client servers.

- Configuring of volume pools, storage units, policies, tape drives and storage units.
- Performing catalog backups andrestores.
- Upgrading and installing of Netbackup Master/Media and clientservers.
- Decommisioning of Media/Client servers from backup environment.
- Working with Netbackup GUI and CLI mode.
- Configuring of SQL,NDMP and VMWARE backups.
- Deduplication, Duplication and SLP configuration
- Troubleshooting of backup failures, drives, tapes, connectivity etc.
- Knowledge of ITILprocess.

Worked with LIC OF INDIA, From June 2013 to August 2014.

Roles and Responsibilities-

Developemnt Officer-

- Worked as a Development officer for LIC to build the team of people(BDM) to get the business for the company.
- Set up the targets for my team and help them to achieve it through the proper leads and guidance.

Worked with [ATS CONSULTANCY SERVICES]. from DEC 2012 to MAY 2013.

Key performance indicators:

- Maintenance /Implementation / troubleshooting of Ericsson BSC and TCSM.
- Commission /Integration /Troubleshooting of 2G BTSsites.
- Planning and Optimisation Engineer having knowledge of Ericsson systemas well.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION:-

□ Certification in VHDL from CETPA Infotech Pvt Ltd, Noida 2011
□ Certification from 509 Army Base Workshop, Agra 2011

EDUCATION & QUALIFICATIONS:-

•	B.Tech(ECE),GBTU.	(69.9%)	2012
•	XII,Agra Public School, Agra	(71.4%)	2008
•	X, Delhi Public School, Agra	(82.6%)	2006

Declaration:

I hereby declare that all the above-mentioned information provided byme is true to the best of my knowledge

Place: Bangalore (Arpit Agarwal)